CHRIS JOHNSON

602-803-6084 | cjohnson@cm.utexas.edu www.crjohnson.me | github.com/crjohn14

PROFILE

Young chemist, with over four years of research experience, transitioning into software development. Experienced solving complex research problems, and teaching at the university level. Driven to become proficient in computer science as shown by three years of course work at UT Austin and on-line.

EDUCATION

2014 - present	CS Coursework : Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Elements of Software Engineering, Data Structures, Intro to Computer Security, Intro to Computer Science, Algorithms and Complexity, Computer Networks, freeCodeCamp.com Front End Development Course
2010 - 2013	The University of Texas at Austin , Austin, TX Master of Arts (Organic Chemistry) - GPA 3.45
2007 - 2010	Arizona State University , Tempe, AZ Bachelor of Science (Chemistry) - GPA 3.47
2005 - 2008	Scottsdale Community College, Scottsdale, AZ Associate of Science - GPA 3.72

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, Python

Web Development: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Jinja2, PHP, Google Cloud Platform

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

Technical Services Supervisor (Department of Chemistry) September 2014 - Present

- Volunteered to write and help build a new on-line training course for Quest Learning & Assessment that provides resources for students and teaching assistants.
- Instructed the lab component of a liberal arts course on the history of alchemy.
- Assist with, and conduct demonstrations for an outreach program in which local high school students participate in chemical analysis at the university.

Graduate Student/Teaching Assistant/Teaching Specialist August 2010 - August 2014

- Synthesized new energy storage materials for use in ultracapacitors and lithium ion batteries.
- Developed new strategies to build complex, conductive polymers.
- Lab Assistant in the Services for Students with Disabilities Department.
- Experienced teaching in both lecture and laboratory settings.

PUBLICATIONS

Miguel Gervaldo, Paul A Liddell, Gerdenis Kodis, Bradley J Brennan, **Christopher Johnson**, James W Bridgewater, Ana L Moore, Thomas A Moore, Devens Gust <u>A photo- and electronically-active porphyrinfullerene dyad electropolymer</u> Photochem. Photobiol. Sci. **2010**, 890-900.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Excellence Award from the UT Austin Department of Chemistry
- Arizona Communication Association Public Speaking Contest Finalist
- Arizona Power Authority Scholarship
- Eagle Scout